A Guide to Dr. Vamik D. Volkan Papers
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Getaway Seminars on Cape Cod (Wellfleet, MA), 1987(8/3-7), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: South Florida Psychiatric Society Symposium on Complicated Mourning and Related States(Miami, Florida), 1988(3/5), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Society of Political Psychology Annual Meeting(New Jersey), 1988(7/1-5), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: New Orleans Psychoanalytic Society Lectures, 1988(12/5), TD (Box-folder 010:015)
  Lecture Schedules
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on psychoanalytic Psychotherapy: Case at Impasse (Maryland), 1989(4/29), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (San Franciscon, CA), 1989(5/3-7), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Presentation on Normal and Pathological Aspects of Mourning (Michigan), 1989(9/23), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:018)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Psychology of International Affairs (Houston, TX), 1990(1/9), TD (Box-folder 010:019)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (New York City), 1990(5/9-13), TD (Box-folder 010:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: New York Freudian Society Scientific Meeting, 1990(6/1), TD (Box-folder 010:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on the Need for Enemies and Allies (University of Pittsburgh), 1990(9/27), pamphlet (Box-folder 010:022)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: The Michael M.Axinn Fifth Annual Memoral Conference: Prejudice (New York), 1990(10/19), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:023)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Normal and Abnormal Mourning (Thomas Jefferson University, PA), 1990(10/27), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:024)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Symposium on the Problem of Ethnicity and Political Change (Charlottesville, vA), 1991(4), TD (Box-folder 010:025)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (New Orleans), 1991(5/8-12), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Object Loss and Regrief Work at Philadelphia Psychiatric Center, 1991(6/4), TD (Box-folder 010:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Ethnicity, Nationalism, and Political Change (Kansas, Lithuania), 1992(4/27-30), TD (Box-folder 010:028)
  Conference Schedules
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Izmir Psychiatry Society Conference: Psychodynamics of Sibling Relations, 1996(11/13), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:029)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Sadism and Masochism (Kuopi University, Finland), 1992(6/1), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Symposium: Integrated Approach to Schizophrenia (Turku, Finland) 1992(6/3-5), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:031)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Society of Political Psychology Annual Meeting (San Francisco), 1992(7/4-8), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:032)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Colloquium: Roots of Prejudice, Hatred, and Violence (Philadelphia, PA) 1992(10/3), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:033)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Workshop - Borderline Personality Organization (Lynchburg, VA) 1993(1/22), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:034)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Violence, Grief, Ethnic Cleansing and War (Charlottesville, VA), 1993(3/3-31), TD (Box-folder 010:035)
  Conference Schedule
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Founder's Day at UVa (Charlottesville, VA), 1993(4/13), pamphlet (Box-folder 010:036)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Health and the Environment 2nd International Conference (United Nations, NY) 1993(4/30), pamphlet (Box-folder 010:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Dr. David's Lecture "The Nazi Phenomenon"(University of Virginia, VA), 1993(5/13), TD (Box-folder 010:038)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: C. Fred Alford's Lecture: Leadership, Groups and Psychoanalysis - The Need to Sacrifice Leaders - (Charlottesville, VA), 1993(4/23), TD (Box-folder 010:039)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Dr. David Rosenfeld's Lecture: Psychosis and Psychotic Parts - A Clinical Investigation of Psychotic Parts of the Personality (Charlottesville, VA), 1993(5/15), TD (Box-folder 010:040)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Psychoanalytical Congress, "The Psychoanalyst's Mind: From Listening to Interpretation" (Amsterdam), 1993(7/25-30), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:041)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Second International Mahler Symposium (Cologne, Germany) "The Develpment and Disorders of Object Constancy", 1993(7/30-8/1), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:042)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Symposium on the Dynamics of Ethnic Conflict in the World: General Reflections and Specific Cases (Bryn Mawr College, PA), 1993(10/1), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:043)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on "Patient Psychotherapy" and "The Psychopathology and Treatment of Complicated Mourning" (Oulu, Finland), 1993(10/18-19), TD (Box-folder 010:044)
  Lecture Program
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Dallas Society for Psychoanalytic Psychology Fall Workshop (Dallas, TX) -"The Psychodynamics of Ethnicity and International Relationships", 1993(11/13), TD (Box-folder 010:045)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Discussion on Recent Advances in the Analysis and Resolution in Xenophobia (Geroge Mason University, VA), 1994(2/18-19), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:046)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (Philadelphia, PA), 1994(5/18-22), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:047)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Today's Youth and Xenophobia (Amsterdam), 1994(6/16-18), pamplet, TD (Box-folder 010:048)
  Reports, Conference Schedules
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Meeting at Hal Saunders' (Washington, D.C.), 1994(7/15), TD (Box-folder 010:049)
  Memo
- Vamik Volkan Papers: IRS Meeting (Charlottesville, VA), 1994(9/11-14), TD, AD (Box-folder 010:050)
  Meeting Program, Memo, Letters
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan's Itinerary of October 1994, 1994(10/18-11/7), TD (Box-folder 010:051)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Borderline Patient Meeting (Torino, Italy), 1994(9/16-17), Pamphlet, TD (Box-folder 010:052)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on a Case of Malignant Narcissism (New Jersey Medical School), 1994(10/19), TD (Box-folder 010:053)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on the Revival of Nationalism (Vienna Psychoanalutic Society), 1994(10/28-29), TD (Box-folder 010:054)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: GAP Meeting (White Plains, NY), 1994(11/3-5), TD (Box-folder 010:055)
  Report
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Hate, Violence and Cultural Identity (Charlottesville, VA), 1994(11/9-11), TD, AD (Box-folder 010:056)
  Letters, Memoradum, Conference Schedules, Report
- Vamik Volkan Papers: World Affairs Council of Philadelphia, 1994(11/17), TD (Box-folder 010:057)
  Letter, Reports, Memo
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Colloquium on Cyprus and Its People (Harvard University, MS), 1994, Tickets, TD (Box-folder 010:058)
  Letter, Colloquium Schedules, Reports
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Fall Meeting(New York), 1994(12/15), TD (Box-folder 010:059)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Workshop on Understanding Racial and Ethnic Conflict (Arlington, VA), 1995(1/5), Pamphlet (Box-folder 010:060)
  Letter, Workshop Announcement
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Seminar on Racism and Anti-Semitism (Istanbul), 1995(1/19-20), Pamphlets, Invitation Note (Box-folder 010:061)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Discussion on Non-Russian Nationalists (UVa, Virginia), 1995(1/19-20), Discussion Announcement (Box-folder 010:062)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan's Lecture on Turks and Greeks - Neighbours in Conflict (NEU, Cyprus), 1995(1/24), Lecture Announcement (Box-folder 010:063)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Carrier Fpundation Symposium on the Many Faces of Grief(New Jersey), 1995(3/22), Pamphlet, TD (Box-folder 011:001)
  Letter, Symposium Schedule
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Society of Plitical Psychology Annual Meeting" (Washington, D.C.), 1995(7/5-9), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:002)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Select Advisory Commission to the FBI's Critical Incident Response Group (Quantico, Virginia), 1996(1/16-18), TD (Box-folder 011:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Psycho-Politcal Meeting (Tallinn, Estonia) 1996(4), TD (Box-folder 011:004)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Interpretation Revisited(San Francisco, CA), 1996(10/12), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:005)
  Pamphlet
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (New York City), 1996(12/18-22), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Research Seminar in Psychiatry, (Muonio, Finland) - "The Modes of Action of the Mind in the Present-day Changing Psychosocial Reality", 1997(3/27-4/1), TD (Box-folder 011:006)
  Seminar Program
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Grief at the Piedmont Chapter (Charlottesville, VA), 1997(4/27), Newsletter (Box-folder 011:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychiatric Association Symposium (San Diego, CA)- "Bosnia-Ancient Fuel for a Murder Inferno", 1997(5/17-22), pamphlet (Box-folder 011:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: The Jessie Ball DuPont Fund Summer Seminars (The National Humanities Cneter, NC), 1997(6/1-20), pamphlet (Box-folder 011:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan's Travel Calendar, October 1997 - November 1999 (New York), 1997(10)-1999(11), TD (Box-folder 011:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Blood Lines: From Ethnic Pride to Terrorism (UCLA, CA), 1997(10/24), Newspaper Clippings (Box-folder 011:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Psychoanalysis and Social Change -Aggressivity and Violence Conference (George Washington University), 1997(11/6-8), TD (Box-folder 011:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Blood Lines: From Ethnic Pride to Terrorism (Emory University), 1997(12/10), Lecture Announcement (Box-folder 011:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting (New York City), 1997(12/17-21), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Annual Academy of Psychoanalysis -41th Winter Meeting (New York City) - "Contributions of Psychoanalysis and Psychodynamic Understanding to Contemporary Life - Critical Issues and Theoretical Framework", 1998(1/8-11), pamphlet, Newsletter (Box-folder 011:015)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference International [ENEL Umbral Del Milenio] (Lima, Peru), 1998(4/15-20), Photo (Box-folder 011:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Dueling Doctrines and the New American Way of War Conference (Washington, D.C.), 1998(6/24-26), TD (Box-folder 011:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference - "Freud at the Millennium"(George Washington University) 1998(10/16-18), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:018)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: First Inter-Regional IPA Conference in Vienna, 1998(11/6-8), Newspaper Article, TD (Box-folder 011:019)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Symposium on the Transgenerational Transmission of Trauma and Its Evolution as an Ethnic Marker (Max-Planck Institute in Gottingen, Germany), 1998(11/12-15), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: 1999(2/27-28, 7/3-4, 11/2o-21), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Health and the Environment International Conference (The United Nations), 1999(4/22-23), TD (Box-folder 011:022)
  Newsletter Article, Report
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Annual Scientific Conference on Psychoanalysis and the Chronologically and Emotionally Challenged (United Nations, NYC), 1999(4/23-24), pamphlet (Box-folder 011:023)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Freud Lectures (University of Vienna) 1999(5/6), pamphlet, TD (Box-folder 011:024)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Psychoanalytic Association Annual Meeting(Washington, D.C.), 1999(5/12-16), pamphlet (Box-folder 011:025)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: American Academy of Psychoanalysis Annual Meeting - "Paradigm Shifts"(Washington, D.C.), 1999(5/13-16), TD (Box-folder 011:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference - Islam and Bosnia, 1999(5/29-30), TD (Box-folder 011:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Group Psychotherapy of Psychotraumatised Persons (Dubrovnik, Croatia), 1999(6/6-12), Pamphlet, TD (Box-folder 011:028)
  Lecture Schedule
- Vamik Volkan Papers: International Psychoanalytic Congress (Santiago, Chile), 1999(7/24-30), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:029)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Concert of Dubrovnik Sympony Orchestra (Croatia), 1999(6/10), Concert Program (Box-folder 011:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Scientific / Practical Conference (Tbilisi, Georgia), 1999(8/9-10), Conference Program (Box-folder 011:031)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: The Medical Center Hour Lectures at UVa (Charlottesville, VA) -"Treating Ethnic Cleansing - Repairing History", 1999(9/22), TD (Box-folder 011:032)
  Lecture Announcements
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Symposium on Breaking the Sprial of Violence (Gottingen, Germany), 1999(11/11-14), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:033)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan Lectures at the Yitzhak Robin Center for Israel Studies), 2000(2/17-5/29), TD (Box-folder 011:034)
  Reports, Lecture Schedules
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Annual Margaret S. Mahler Symposium on Child Development (Locust, PA), 2000(5/6), TD (Box-folder 011:035)
  Symposium Program
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan's Lecture - "What the Study of Borderline Personality Organization Tells Us About International Relationships" (Munchen, Germany), 2000(11/19), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:036)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Passing the Baton: Challeges of Statecraft for the New Administration (Washington, D.C.), 2001(1/17), TD (Box-folder 011:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: The Medical Center Hour Lectures at UVA (Charlottesville, VA), 2001(1/24), Lecture Announcement (Box-folder 011:038)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: 3RD International Congress for Family and Human Systems Constellation - Fields of Conflict, Fields of Wisdom, 2001(5/14), Pamplet (Box-folder 011:039)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Workshop on Black and Caspian Sea Collaborative Research Program (Istanbul, Turkey), 2001(8/3-4), TD (Box-folder 011:040)
  Workshop Program
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Virginia Psychoanalytic Society Case Conference Seminar (CMSHI), 2001(10/17), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:041)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Annual Conference on Psychoanalysis and Creativity: Me and My Baby - Identity and Creativity (NC Bar Center), 2001(11/2-4), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:042)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Conference on Peacemaking with Justice: Policy for the 21st Century (San Diego, CA), 2001(12/6-7), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:043)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: 2002(3), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:044)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture on Religious Fundamentalism and Violence (Plymouth, NH), 2002(10/21), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:045)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: IAGP Pre-Congress Workshop (Berlin, Germany) - "When Enemies Meet: Large Group Trauma and Identity", 2003(10/2-5), TD (Box-folder 011:046)
  Letter, Reports
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lucy Daniels Foundation Lecture (NC): The Psychology of Terror, 2004(5/13-15), Lecture Announcement (Box-folder 011:047)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Volkan's Presentation - "The Interwinning of External and Internal Wars", 2004(10/16-17), Pamphlet (Box-folder 011:048)
- Vamik Volkan Papers: Lecture and Booksigning - Religion, Fundamentalism and Violence, 2004(11/12), Announcement of Lecture and Booksigning (Box-folder 011:049)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Letters from Rauf R. Denktas and Photographs of "Neutralised" Turkish Cypriots", 1996, TD (Box-folder 011:050)
  Letters, Photocopied Photos
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Volkan's Review of Gus Feissel's Paper, "The Origins of the Cyprus Problem", 1998, TD (Box-folder 011:051)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Report on the Turkish-Greek Dialogue Meetings I-IV, 1998-2001, TD (Box-folder 011:052)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Report on the Turkish Meeting (Charlottesville, VA), 1999(4/19-21), TD (Box-folder 011:053)
  Report, Letter, List of Dialogue Participants
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Greek Meeting (Charlottesville, VA), 2000(1/22-25), TD (Box-folder 011:054)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Budget and Funding for the First Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in October 2000, 2000(2/29-11/28), TD, AD (Box-folder 012:001)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Correspondence in Preparation of the First Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in October 2000, 2000(3/31-10/18), TD, AD (Box-folder 012:002)
  Reports, Letters
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Greek-Turkish Forum [Issues on the Aegean], 2000(6/23), TD (Box-folder 012:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Professor Nanette Neuwahl's Draft - "Cyprus Which Way - In Pursuit of a Confederal Solution in Europe", 2000(7), TD (Box-folder 012:004)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Report on the First Joint Turkish-Greek Meeting, "Workshop on History, Identity, and Contemporary Conflicts" (Caux, Switzerland), 2000(10/23-25), TD (Box-folder 012:005)
  Reports, Participants List
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Correspondence after the First Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in October 2000, 2000(11/2-12/14), TD (Box-folder 012:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Correspondence in Preparation of the Second Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in October 2001, 2001(7/9-9/25), TD, AD (Box-folder 012:007)
  Letters, CV of Dr. Grigorios Siomopoulos
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Report on the Second Joint Turkish-Greek Meeting (Istanbul, Turkey), 2001(10/3-7), TD (Box-folder 012:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Correspondence after the Second Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in October 2001, 2001(10/11), TD (Box-folder 012:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Correspondence in Preparation of the Third Joint Greek-Turkish Meeting in June 2002, 2001(11/18-21), TD, AD (Box-folder 012:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Report on the Third Joint Turkish-Greek Meeting (Thessaloniki, Greece), 2002(6/20-24), TD (Box-folder 012:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Turkish Daily News Article, "Turkish-Greek Prejudices(I)", 2002(7/3), TD (Box-folder 012:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Turkish Daily News Article, "Identity and the Cyprus Issue(II)", 2002(7/4), TD (Box-folder 012:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Turkish-Greek Project: Wall Street Journal Article, "The EU's Date with History in Copenhagen", 2002(12/4), TD (Box-folder 012:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Vytautas J. Bieliauskas, 1991(4/3), TD (Box-folder 012:015)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Ambassador Oleg G. Peressypkin, 1991(9/26), TD (Box-folder 012:016)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Ambassador Oleg G. Peressypkin, 1991(11/20), TD (Box-folder 012:017)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnicity, Nationalism and Political Change (Lithuania), 1992(4/27-30), TD (Box-folder 012:018)
  Reports, Letters, Memoranda
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: List of Participants at Riga Conference, 1993(4/5-8), TD (Box-folder 012:019)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Grand Proposal, March 1993-August 1994: Ethnicity, Nationalism and Political Change - Baltic Project, 1993-1994, TD (Box-folder 012:020)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence in the United States, 1994(3/5-6), TD (Box-folder 012:021)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence III(Tallinn, Estonia), 1994(4/7), TD (Box-folder 012:022)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Baltic Project - Trip to Estonia, 1994(4/12), TD (Box-folder 012:023)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Carl-Eric Brattemo, 1993(7/7), TD (Box-folder 012:024)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Journal Article from CSMHI News - "Estonia Revisited", 1994(Fall), TD (Box-folder 012:025)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Trip Report to Norway and Estonia, 1994(10/2-15), TD (Box-folder 012:026)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence IV(Parnu, Estonia), 1994(10/10-13), TD (Box-folder 012:027)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence V(Tallinn, Estonia), 1995(2/10-11), TD (Box-folder 012:028)
  List of Participants
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Final Report on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence [Baltic Project], 1995(3), TD (Box-folder 012:029)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Letters from Ants Paju, 1995(3/20), TD (Box-folder 012:030)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project Report: "An Overview of Environmental Problems in Estonia", 1995(4/24), TD (Box-folder 012:031)
  Reports, Maps, Photos
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: CSMHI Workshop Participants and Contacts in Estonia, 1995(5/5), TD, AD, Namecards (Box-folder 012:032)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence VI(Tallinn, Estonia), 1995(9/10-14), TD (Box-folder 012:033)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Schedule for the Site Investigation Trip, 1995(9/15), TD (Box-folder 012:034)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Newspaper Articles, 1995, Newspaper Articles (Box-folder 012:035)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Report on Estonia University Students' Visit to Charlottesville, 1996(2/4-7), TD (Box-folder 012:036)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Students and Professors in "Ecologicla Security of Estonia", 1996(3/1-2), TD (Box-folder 012:037)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference on Ethnic Pluralism, Racism and Violence VIII(Tallinn, Estonia), 1996(4/22-24), TD (Box-folder 012:038)
  Reports, List of Participants
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Extension of Baltics Conflict Prevention Project, 1995(5/3), TD (Box-folder 012:039)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Report to USIS-Tallinn, "Workshop on Teaching Speaking to Estonian as a Second Language Learners", 1996(12/9-21), TD (Box-folder 012:040)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Documentary Film from Allan King, "The Dragon's Egg", 1997(3/18), TD (Box-folder 013:001)
  pamphlets
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Invitation to the Independence Day Garden Party, 1997(7/4), TD (Box-folder 013:002)
  Invitation Card
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from the Estonian Parliament, 1997(7/5), TD (Box-folder 013:003)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Draft of Estonia Proposal and Two-Year Budget, 1998(1/12), TD (Box-folder 013:004)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Endel Talvik (Subject: Language Book), 1998(1/21), TD (Box-folder 013:005)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project Report: "The Development of Methodology for Conflict Prevention: the Case of Estonia", 1998(6), TD (Box-folder 013:006)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Memorandum on Recent Development at Mustvee, Klooga and Mustamae, 1998(8/21), TD (Box-folder 013:007)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Endel Talvik, 1998(9/16-11/3), TD (Box-folder 013:008)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Endel Talvik, 1998(12/21), TD (Box-folder 013:009)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project Report: "From Dialogue to Action in the Balkans: Psychopolitical Strategies for Reconciliation and Reconstruction", 1999(1), TD (Box-folder 013:010)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter from Endel Talvik, 1999(1/20), TD (Box-folder 013:011)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project:Letter from Endel Talvik, 1999(2/11), TD (Box-folder 013:012)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Endel Talvik's Report, "Civic Society in Estonia", 1999(3), TD (Box-folder 013:013)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Conference, "Frm Dialogue to Action: Models of Ethnic Reconcilation and Civil Society Building in Estonia", 1999(4/30-5/1), TD (Box-folder 013:014)
- Vamik Volkan Papers - Estonia Project: Letter to Endel Talvik, 1999(7/13), TD (Box-folder 013:015)